Finding Aid for Center for Japanese Studies (University of Michigan) Records 1945-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio-Visual Materials 1945-1991, 3 linear feet
  - Slides, 4 folders; 25 sheets
    - Slides of Village Japan
      - Orayama
        - Orayama-near Kurashiki city-Mani Shopping St. August 1950, KA4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Oku-gun, Owari-Kadota Shell mound April 1950, KA5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Waterwheel May 1950, KB1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Shimotsui rest hotel May 1950, KB2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Vakake May 1950, KB3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Yoshii River, April. 1950, KB4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Thmashima March 1950, KB5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-near Okutsu hot springs April 1950, KC1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Kurashiki, Ohara's mansion April 1950, KC2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-near Kurashiki, grass mats drying May 1950, KC3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Inland Sea near Shimotisui March 1950, KC4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-terraces on slope near Shkuma March 1950, KC5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Smoldering charcoal-burning bus, August 27, KD1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Takamatsu Elem.-school children October 1950, KD2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Chinomiya-fire brigade March 1950, KD3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Minamigata March 1950, KD4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
        - Orayama-Asahi Press Bldg. August 10, 1950, KD5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 15)
      - Okayama City
        - Okayama City-Musician Cart April 1950, LA1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Okayama City-Koboji (temple)--festival May 1950, LA2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Okayama City-Tamashima-head priest of Ensuji March 1950, LA3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Okayama City-Juio-sam. by his work of art August 26, 1951, LA4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Okayama City-Tamashima, Entsugi (temple) March 1950, LA5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Okayama City-Sogenji (Zin temple) November 1950, LB1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Staff at Center for J. Studies November 1950, LB2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Okayama-Yokake honjin (fendal inn) May 1950, LB3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Okayama City-Takashima-charring bottom of fishing boat July 1950, LB4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
      - Tokyo
        - Tokyo-Imperial Palace plaza-Dai Ichi Bldg. March 1951, MA1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Tokyo-Imperial Palace plaza-bridge March 1951, MA2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Tokyo-Binzo-street scene August 1951, MA3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Tokyo-Shimbachi August 1951, MA4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Tokyo-Akabusa-big movie house August 1951, MA5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Tokyo-Hibuya Park March 1951, MB1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Tokyo-Imperial Hotel March, 1951, MB2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Tokyo-Binza-new building August 1951, MB3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
      - Kyoto
        - Kyoto-festival at Hietian Shrine April 1950, MC1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Kyoto-street scene June 1951, MC2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
        - Kyoto-festival at Hietian Shrine April 1950, MC3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 16)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Hishashiyama-Mori Castle ruins August 23, 1951, NA1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - , Marugama-Shikoku-tori pattern-south November 24, 1951, NA2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Kamakura-Daibutsu August 1951, NA3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Shimotsui-resort hotel August 1951, NA4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Nara-Todaijo kondo October 1950, NA5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Soja-cho-priest & Mr. Taniguchi before temple's pagoda August 1951, NB1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Kyoto-Heian-style cart in Jidai Matsuri October 1950, NB2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Kamakura-main gate, Hachiman Shrine August 1951, NB3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Kyoto-court of Heian Jingu October 1950, NB4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Koboji October 1950, NB5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Kojima-shi Shrine, Hachiman October 1950, NC1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - -Kamakura-Daibutsu March 1950, NC2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Toru-approach to Toshogu August 1950, NC3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Tsukubo, Shoson April 1950, NC4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - -Hiramatsu Sensei April 1950, NC5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Hakata-semi-commercial bion festival, July 1-14 1950, ND1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Osarva Castle April 1950, ND2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Kihara granddaughters in No costume April 1950, ND3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Tainarsu-lighting in grave plot, 1st night of Bion festival, ND4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - ceremonial objects on shelves, ND5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 18)
        - Beardsley as samurai May 1950, OA1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Amano kashidate-bridge June 1951, OA2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Harjo-chi-salt field along coast August 1951, OA3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Hashirijina-drying shrimp nets August 1950, OA4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Ikura-political campaign speech by Station April 1951, OA5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Enoshina-causeway August 1951, OB1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Kamakura-Prof. Beardsley, Hall, Coheste & wife March 1950, OB2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Tamatsukuri-Chorakuen Inn bath house June 1951, OB3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Sanindo-Naoe-paddy June 1951, OB4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Ohishima boats in cove August 1950, OB5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Shimobayashi-approach with lotus pond September 1950, OC1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Minamikan-garden, Matsue, Shinane key August 1950, OC2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Karsura garden-teahouse August 1950, OC3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Unzen-hotsprings December 1950, OC4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Senzoker-hanging noodles to dry by rack November 1950, OC5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Kamahura-Great Buddna August 1951, OD1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Sanatzn-cherry blossoms April 1950, CD2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Ikura-from plateau April 1951, OD3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Tsutsu-Ogi Ryuho (priest), Sudo Seitaro (kuzo) at hotel, OD4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Cryptomeair Avenue leading fun Toshogu-to Futa-arasan, Jinsa August 1950, CD5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 19)
        - Kamo-son, July 5 1950, PA (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Takahashi River from K. March 1950, PA2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Kamakura, Hachiman-gu entrance March 1950, PA3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Kasuga no Miya Nara April 1950, PA4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Shurakuen at Shimatsu March 1950, PA5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Kibitsu-Jinja November 1950, PB1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Kurashiki-Shrine April 1950, PB2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Sea of Japan August 1950, PB3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Mihajima May 1950, PB4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Lake Hakone, or Takaido Rd., Mach 1950, PB5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - S.S. Gen. Gordon, mid-Pacific Sunset, view to east March 1950, PC1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Koshin-san view. Valley of Ashimori River June 1950, PC2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Fukuoka-Matsuri palaguin tying up traffic July 1950, PC3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Naked festival participants February 1951, PC4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - -Kojima-shi Street procession October 1950, PC5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - morning view from our window November 1950, PD1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Kochi-point at Karsurahama October 1950, PD2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Kibitsu procession November 1950, PD3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Sakadzu-flower viewing April 1950, PD4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Shimobayashi-togarashi drying September 1950, PD5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 20)
        - Hashihama-Shikoku coast from island May 1950, QA1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Shimotsu-center's fishing trip July 1950, QA2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Takahashi River-falls November 1950, QA3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Palace Garden, Katsura detached from April 1950, QA4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Kochi-point at Katsurahama October 1950, QA5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Kojima-Shi. Hama-Kampyot fish drying August 1950, QB1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Horen-peasant house September 1950, QB2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Tsushima-Magere-woman diver August 1950, QB3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Nara Todarji-Honden April 1950, QB4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Kamakura-Daibutsu March 1950, QB5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Miyajima May 1950, QC1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Miyajimaen route to May 1950, QC2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - our apt. at K(amakura?) November 1950, QC3 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - drying willet and kura at K(amakura?) November 1950, QC4 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Nara Park-Kasuga no-Miza Temple April 1950, QC5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Fishing boats at (blank) August 1950, QD1 (Box 16, Othertype No. 21)
        - Miscellaneous Unidentified slides of Japan, RA1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 22)
        - Miscellaneous Unidentified slides of Japan, RB1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 22)
        - Miscellaneous Unidentified slides of Japan, RC1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 22)
        - Miscellaneous Unidentified slides of Japan, RD1-2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 22)
        - Unidentified slides of Korea, SAl-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 23)
        - Unidentified slides of Korea, SB1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 23)
        - Unidentified slides of Korea, SC1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 23)
        - Unidentified slides of Korea, TA1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 24)
        - Unidentified slides of Korea, TB1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 24)
        - Unidentified slides of Korea, TC1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 24)
        - Unidentified slides of Korea, TD1-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 24)
        - unidentified slides, UAl-5 (Box 16, Othertype No. 25)
        - unidentified slides, UB1-2 (Box 16, Othertype No. 25)
    - Book 1, Agriculture, Environment, Education, Geographical Setting (Box 19)
    - Book 2, History and Art (Kamakura to Present), Housing, Leisure (Box 19)
    - Book 3, Life, Music and Drama, Literature, Occupations, Politics, Clothing, Food, Religion, Transportation (Box 19)
    - Okayama, Japan Field Station House and Room photographs 1950s, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Event Photographs 1997-2003 (Box 19)
    - Mochi Party Photographs 1/22/2003 (Box 19)
    - Edward Putzar
      - Japanese Religious Life: Text to Accompany 432 color slides on Contemporary and Historical Dimensions of Japanese Religion 1972 (Box 19)
      - Japanese Religions Slides
  - Audio Tapes
    [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
    - Japanese Area Studies; Planning Conference, 1963 May 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3.75 ips
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-1-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; Box reads Takahashi and in Japanese. Male and female speaker speaking in Japanese.)
      - [Part 2], [8742-SR-1-2]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; Box reads Takahashi and in Japanese. Male and female speaker speaking in Japanese.)
    - Japanese Area Studies; Planning Conference, 1963 May 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-2-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; Various speakers discussing the logistics of studying abroad in Japan.)
    - Japanese Area Studies; Planning Conference, 1963 May 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-3-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 3; Recording is very quiet. Various speakers speaking in Japanese.)
      - [Part 2], [8742-SR-3-2]; mp3 file; (Tape 3; Recording is very quiet. Various speakers speaking in Japanese.)
    - Japanese Area Studies; Planning Conference, 1963 May 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-4-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 4; Various speakers speaking in Japanese.)
      - [Part 2], [8742-SR-4-2]; mp3 file; (Tape 4; Various speakers speaking in Japanese.)
    - Japanese Area Studies; Planning Conference, 1963 May 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-5-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 5; Various speakers discussing American - Japanese relations.)
    - Japanese Area Studies; Planning Conference, 1963 May 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-6-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 6; Various speakers discussing American Studies programs in Japan and English Language Instruction.)
    - Robert E. Ward, “Area Studies and the Center for Japanese Studies,” Matsumoto Shigeki, Undated, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-7-1]; mp3 file; (Various speakers discussing in Japanese.)
      - [Part 2], [8742-SR-7-2]; mp3 file; (Various speakers discussing in Japanese.)
    - Okayama Field Station 1, [Between 1950-1955], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-8-1]; mp3 file; (Various speakers discussing in Japanese.)
      - [Part 2], [8742-SR-8-2]; mp3 file; (Various speakers discussing in Japanese.)
    - Okayama Field Station 2, [Between 1950-1955], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [8742-SR-9-1]; mp3 file; (Selection of musical performances from Japan including singing and orchestral music.)
  - Films (16 mm), circa 1950-1955
    - Fishing and Funeral. Tsutsu, 6 inch reel (Box 17)
    - Niike: Irrigation and Rice Culture, 9 inch reel, U-Matic video available (Box 17)
    - Hills and Lady Tying Flax, 6 inch reel, U-Matic video available (Box 17)
    - [not present] (Box 17)
    - Niike-Jijin-matsuri Irrigation (Box 17)
    - Kids, Farm Family, 6 inch reel (Box 17)
    - Tsutsu-Jibikami (Box 17)
    - 10 Short Films of Japanese Life and Agriculture, 12 inch reel, original Kodachrome (Box 17)
    - [not present] (Box 17)
    - Hills Panorama and compost kegs, 6 inch reel, U-Matic video available (Box 17)
    - Tsutsu (Box 17)
    - (Unnumbered film) Rice Farming in Japan, 6 inch reel, U-Matic video available (Box 17)
    - (Unnumbered film) On Rice Production, 6 inch reel (Box 17)
  - DVDs and CDs
    - Beate Sirota Gordon, "Drafting the Woman's Rights Clause for the New Constitution, DVD (Box 18)
    - Tokyo Trial Lecture, DVD (Box 18)
    - Mariko Okada and Kiju Yoshida, C.C. Little Symposium Photo (Box 18)
    - Okada and Yoshida, Film Screening Post, Photo CD (Box 18)
    - Master Copy-Okada and Yoshida (Box 18)
      (4 sets photos-Film Screening, Symposium, Party)
    - Noon Lecture Series Presents: "Mad Amano, Little Boy and Fat Man: The Myth of Dropping the Atomic Bombs. Who is the real devil?" January 19, 2006, DVD (Box 18)